Previously on Z Nation.
[growling] [screaming]
이 남자는 좀비한테 물려도
살아남는 법을 유일하게 알고있어요
(Warren) This man is the only
known survivor of a zombie bite.
He's our last best hope for humanity.
그는 인류의 마지막이자
최후의 희망이에요
What if I don't want to be your guinea pig?
내가 당신에 기니피그를
원하지 않으면 어쩔거지?
그럼 당신은 환자를 거의
없게 만들어야 할거에요
Then you'll wind up like
patient zero over there.
I've led them into a trap.
Kill him.
그를 죽여
[gunfire]
(10K) Doc!
박사!
(Murphy) You set me up you bastard.
You set me up you bastard.
I had no idea this was gonna happen.
머리가 하얘, 일이 어떻게 되가는거야
You have to believe me.
넌 날 믿어야돼
No I don't.
아니 그렇겐 못해
난 그 어떤것과 어떤사람도
못믿는다고 또 말하고 있잖아
I don't have to believe
anything anyone says ever again.
A tactical nuclear weapon
will be launched from NORAD
전술핵무기가 노라드에서 가동될거야
연구실을 소각하게 될거야
to incinerate the lab.
(computer voice) Seven
minutes to detonation.
7분뒤에 폭파됩니다
(Doc) Is that all that's left of Murphy?
전부야? 모두 머피에서 나왔나?
주인공은 피부를 없앨거야
(주인공 이름을 모르겠다)
He shed his skin.
Holy crap.
죶됨
Look.
봐봐
Lets go.
가자
God I hate the Apocalypse.
죶됨 파멸 개싫어하는데
[alarm beeping]
[alarm continues] [melancholy
guitar music plays]
♪
[muffled explosion]
[explosion]
♪
[loud explosion]
[snarling]
♪
[brakes screeching]
[splat]
Sorry!
미안
♪
[engine revving]
[explosion]
♪
[engine revving]
[explosion]
♪
[electric guitar
theme music plays]
♪ Have mercy.
[three gunshots]
♪
♪ Oh, have mercy. ♪
- Sync and corrected by TheDelta -
- www.addic7ed.com -
[wind blowing]
[grunting]
[Doc moaning]
[moaning] Watch the shoulder.
어깨를 봐
죶도 씨발
Holy shit.
Is that snow?
눈이냐?
Nah, that's not snow.
아니 눈 아닌듯
That's ash.
재다
Radioactive fallout.
방사능을 함유한 맛있는 재인듯
[breathing heavily]
[wind blowing]
[snarling]
[gunshot]
[sigh]
[clank]
[gunshot]
[whispering] Crap.
쓰레기 새퀴들
[blowing wind continues]
[metal creaking]
[snarling]
[growling]
[snarling continues]
[gunshot]
[growling continues]
[splorch]
[thud]
[breathing heavily]
[snarling]
[gasp]
[growling]
[grunting]
[clunk]
[crash]
[zombie growling] [Citizen
Z breathing heavily]
[growling]
[whimpering]
[gunshot]
[thud]
[breathing heavily]
[coughing]
This is Citizen Z broadcasting
on all frequencies.
모든 주파수에서 방송되는 "시민Z" 입니다
This is an emergency broadcast.
이건 비상방송입니다
Repeat. This is an emergency broadcast.
반복하지만, 이건 비상방송입니다
Literally life and death for the human race.
말그대로 삶과 죽음 생존을 위한 것 입니다
Now there's a man traveling among you.
지금 그속에서 여행중인 남자가 있습니다
He's the only human known to
have survived a zombie bite.
이 남자는 좀비한테 물려도
살아남는 법을 유일하게 알고있습니다
His blood has the antibodies
to create a vaccine.
그가 가진 피는 면역체고
백신을 만들수 있습니다
Now it is imperative that he
be transported alive
지금 그가 살아서 도착하는게
굉장히 중요합니다
to the Centers for Disease
Control Lab in California.
캘리포니아에 있는
질병제어 센터로 말입니다
[crash]
[snarling]
His name is Murphy.
Last seen in Fort Collins, Colorado.
그의 이름은 뭘픠, 마지막으로 콜로라도
콜린스 항구에서 보았습니다
Six foot two. Dark hair.
Numerous bite marks on torso.
183센치에 어두운 머리
몸통에 몇몇 물린자욱이 있습니다
Known to control zombies.
좀비들을 어떻게
제어하는지 알고있습니다
Should be considered armed and dangerous.
신중해야합니다. 무장을 했고 위험합니다
Keep alive at all costs. Repeat.
무슨수를 써서라도
살려야합니다. 반복합니다
Keep him alive at all costs.
무슨 수를 써서라도 살려야합니다
[growling]
The Centers for Disease Control
is offering an enormous bounty
질병제어 센터는
거대한 포상금을 내놓았습니다
for Murphy's safe delivery
멀픠를 안전하게 데려다줄
사람에게 말입니다
당신의 요구조건을
무엇이든지 들어줄 것 입니다
to be paid in whatever form you desire,
as well as being first in
line for any cure developed.
게다가 개발되는
백신으로 치료해 줄 겁니다
[snarling]
[whispering] If you can hear this broadcast
만약 당신이 이 방송을 듣고있다면..
Save humanity. Save yourself.
당신 손으로... 인류를 구해주세요
Find Murphy.
멀퓌를 찾으세요
[snarling]
[splorch]
[breathing heavily]
They're all dead.
다 뒈졌어
How?
어떻게?
We were on the hill
watching the lights.
언덕에 있었는데 불빛을 봤어
내 생각엔 핵폭탄들이야
I think those were nukes.
저게 뭘까 생각했었어
That's what I thought.
Figured what was left of the
world was trying to kill itself.
결과적으로 우리 스스로가 세계를 망쳤어
어쨋든 소년은 그들을 멀리보냈어
왜냐면 서른번은 돌아섰었거든?
Anyway, the boy they banished
because he turned thirteen?
걔는 돌아왔을때
He figured it out.
이런 결과를 냈어
Came back.
Set the whole place on fire
이곳의 모든걸 이불태워 버렸어
and released the zombie bear.
그리고 좀비곰을 풀어줘버렸어
Well sounds like she was right about men.
그말은 마치 그년이
사람들에게 옳게 했었던거 같군
Look, Mack
멕 봐봐
[roaring]
Bear?
곰?
응
[whispering] Yeah.
Are you coming or not?
갈래 말래?
[motor starting]
[motor running]
[upbeat music playing]
♪
[snarling]
Come along, little doggies.
다 왔다. 개새끼들아
I found a new set of digs
I think you're gonna like.
새롭운 통로를 찾아냈어
내 생각엔 니가 좋아할거 같아
헤이, 너를 캘러웨이로 끌고 갈거야
Hey, that's a real set of
Callaways you're dragging there.
좀 존중해라
Have some respect.
Hey, friend.
이봐 친구
[snarling]
Friend?
친구?
쇼핑 좀 더할까? 엉?
Doing a little shopping, huh?
President's Day Sale.
대통령의 날 세일이야
[snarling]
좀비들을 잘꼬셨네
These zombies of yours are pretty tame.
얘넨 내 좀비들이 아냐
They're not my zombies.
I would never own a
난 결코 소유하지 않았지
Can I help you... friend?
내가 좀 도와줄까 친구?
넌 그냥 밖으로 나갈 수 있어
You can start by stepping aside.
[gunshot]
What the hell did you do that for?
왜 그랬어 슈방
Your name Murphy?
니 이름이 멀퓌냐?
Nope.
아니
(Citizen Z on recording)
His name is Murphy.
그의 이름은 멀퓌
Last seen in Fort Collins,
Colorado.
마지막으로 콜로라도
콜린스항구에서 봤습니다
185센치에 어두운 머리색
몸통에 몇몇 물린 자국이 있습니다
Six foot two. Dark hair.
Numerous bite marks on torso.
좀비들을 제어하는 법을 알고 있씁니다
Known to control zombies.
Should be considered
armed and dangerous.
신중해야하며 무장했고, 위험합니다
무슨 수를 써서 살려야합니다
반복합니다. 무슨수를 써서 살ㄹ..
Keep alive at all costs.
Repeat. Keep him ali...
You're sure you're not The Murphy?
너 멀퓌라는거 ㅇㅈ?
지금 당장은 널 살려둬야 해
Cuz right now that's the
only thing keeping you alive.
Show me your bites.
물린 자국좀 보여줄래?
I beg your pardon?
뭐라고??
들었잖아~
Your heard me.
셔츠 벗어
물린 자국들을 봐야돼
Lift up your shirt.
I need to see those bites.
니가 진짠지 자국들이 있는지 말이지
Got to make sure you're the real thing.
물린 자국들이지?
Those are bites?
They were.
They're healing nicely, thank you.
그들은 치료되고 있어. 고마워
그래, 어쨋든 내가 멀퓌라면
Okay, so what if I am The Murphy,
뭐 어쨋든 이 지옥은 뭐냐?
whatever the hell that means. So what?
[laughing] So everybody and
their uncle's looking for you.
모두 널 찾고 있어
정부는 니 몸뚱아리에
거대한 포상금을 걸었다고
Government is paying a bounty on your ass.
[laughs] Look, I got a whole van
full of oxy if that's what you want.
이봐, 난 산소로 가득찬 밴을
갖고있어 너가 갖길 원한다면
반을 가져가 그리고 난 내 갈길을 갈게?
How 'bout you take half
and I'll just be on my way?
어떡하지 난 산소통이랑 너랑
캘리포니아가서 포상금도 탈건데?
How 'bout I take the oxy and you
to California for that bounty?
니가 날 캘리포니아에 데려간다고?
You're gonna take me to California?
By yourself?
니가?
이 씨발
Damn straight.
[laughs]
[laughing] Sorry. Sorry.
미안, 미안 ㅋㅋ
넌 미친놈인듯
You're insane.
[clicking of taser] [moaning]
That's right. I'm insane.
그래 씨발 나 미친놈이다
You're my prisoner.
넌 내 포로야
걱정은 하지마 멀퓌 널 죽이고 싶진않아
Don't worry Mr. Murphy, I won't kill you.
그런데 널 다치게는 할거야
But I will hurt you
내가 필요로 하면 진짜로 씹새끼처럼
알아 들었냐?
real bad if I need to.
Do you understand me?
너가..
Do you...
[stab]
카센드라?
Cassandra?
Oh, I didn't know if I'd ever see you again.
Oh, I didn't know if I'd
ever see you again.
[hissing]
[moans] Oh, okay.
오, 알았어
Yeah, good to see you too.
알았어 나도 반갑다고
All right, come on.
Let's break it up here. Okay.
맞아 이리와
그만하고 내려와봐, 그래
폭탄~~
[stuttering] Bomb
폭탄.. 폭탄 그래 안좋았지
Bomb. Bomb, bad. Yeah.
들어봐 여긴 안전하지 않아
밖으로 나갈 필요가 있어 알겠지?
Listen. It's not safe here.
We need to get out of here, okay?
But first, you need a makeover, girl.
그러기전에 너 좀 꾸며야겠다
[growling]
No, no. No.
안돼 안돼 안돼
No mercy for that one.
걔한테 자비를 베풀지마
[growling continues]
쟤를 위한 계획이 있어 이리와
I got plans for him. Come on.
[growling continues]
응, 이것들 중에서 잘 가져가야돼
Yeah, well you should've thought about that
그전에 넌 아무 잘못없는
좀비들을 쐈지, 안그랬어?
before you shot those innocent zombies,
shouldn't you have?
이것 좀 봐봐
Let me see.
예아
Yeah.
내가 얘기했었지 하얀밍크는
모두를 끌리게 한다고, 안그래?
I told you that white mink would
pull it all together, didn't I?
Classy.
고급져
고오급져어
[whispering] Classy.
Let's get out of here.
갖고 나가자
가요 개나쁜 새끼씨
Come along, mister I'm So Badass.
Let's go.
ㄱㄱ
[groaning]
그래 요 위에서 좀 쉬어
Okay. Let's get you over here.
[groaning]
What is it?
이거 뭐야?
The bleeding stopped, but
출혈을 멎게해줘
그냥 가
Just go.
Find me a hole to crawl in.
죽게 내버려둬
Leave me a weapon and some ammo.
탄약이랑 무기랑 챙겨서 떠나
이봐
Hey.
너가 뒤지기 전에 아무도 안떠난다고
Nobody's leaving you here to die.
조금 남은 물이나 마셔
Here, take the last of the water.
Go on. Pretty weak myself.
가자. 내스스로가 너무 약해졌어
We wait here too long,
we might be too weak to go look for help.
너무 오래 기다렸더니 많이 쇠약해졌고
더 기력이 떨어지기 전에 가서 도움요청을 해야돼
I've only got a day in me without water,
if that.
물없인 하루도 못버텨 만약 그렇게 되면
잘 생각안나
난 어디로든 가야돼
Well I don't think I'm going anywhere,
Chief.
10K, you stay here with Doc.
넌 여기서 박사랑 기다려
I'm going to see if I can find food or help
난 가서 힘이 남아 있는 동안 음식이랑
while I still got the strength.
도움요청할 수 있는지 보고 올게
If I'm not back in 48 hours,
내가 48시간 안에 안돌아오면
you're on your own.
너 자신을 잘 지켜
Good luck.
운빨 따르길 바래
고맙네
Thanks
[growling]
[dog barks]
[whispering] Shhh. I know, pup. I am too.
쉬~~ 나도 알아, 나도 눈치챘어
(Citizen Z on radio) This
is an emergency broadcast.
Repeat.
This is an emergency broadcast.
Literally life and death
for the human race.
(recording continues) There is a man
traveling among you he's the only human
known to have survived
a zombie bite
만약 이 일이
(Mack) If this works,
Warren and the others will be able to see the signal for miles.
Warren and the others will be
able to see the signal for miles
뭐 좀 찾았어?
Find something?
아니. 이건 그냥 계속 반복된 녹음방송이야
No. It's just that same recorded
broadcast again and again.
I hope he's okay up there.
그가 괜찮길 바랄뿐야
Nine, eight, eight, three, four.
(different voice on radio) Nine,
eight, eight, three, four.
Just that same weird numbers station again.
이상한 숫자만 반복돼
이 짧은 코드들 알어?
You know that's got to be some sort of code.
누군가 요즘 비밀이
알려지지 않길 바라나봐
Wonder who needs to keep a secret anymore.
(male speaking in
Spanish on radio)
(female speaking in
Mandarin on radio)
[whispering] What?
뭐?
Who was that?
누가 뭐라는겨?
I don't know,
but they were talking about Murphy.
모르겠어 그런데
멀퓌에 대해서 말한거 같아
It was something in Spanish and I dunno,
maybe Mandarin.
이건 스페인어고 모르겠고, 아마 관료인듯
Do you think that means he's still alive?
그가 아직 살아있을지 생각해봤어?
The question is
그 질문은..
do we really still care if he's alive?
만약에 살아있다면
우리가 도와줄 수 있을까?
If you don't care if he's still alive,
너가 만약 못 돌봣으면
만약에 걔가 아직 살아있다면
why are you trying to contact
Warren and the others, huh?
왜 넌 워렌과 다른애들을
자꾸 만나려는거야 ?
Got nothing else to do, Addy.
그거 밖에 할게 없으니까 에디
[grunt]
[breathing deeply]
[whispering] Come on, Warren.
이리와 워렌
Don't die
뒈지지마
before you can kill yourself.
그전에 자살할 수 있어
[breathing deeply]
[whispering] Three more
bullets than I need.
3발 이상 필요한데
[click]
[whispering] Sorry, Doc.
미안 덕
Sorry, 10K.
미안 텐케이
I tried.
난 노력했어
난 노력했다구..
[click]
[whispering] Lieutenant Roberta Warren.
리우테넌ㅌ 로베ㄹ타 워렌
I
난..
Give you mercy.
네게 자비를 베푼다..
[distant screaming]
도와주삼!
(girl) Help me!
Help!
도와줭
[snarling]
[growling]
[growling continues]
[thump]
[slice]
[snarling]
[thud]
[gunshot]
[growling and snarling]
[splorch]
[growling]
[growling continues]
[thud]
[slice]
[splorch]
[growling]
[stab]
[gunshot]
[splorch]
[stab]
[gunshot]
[growling]
[thud]
[snarling]
[splorch]
[breathing heavily]
[growling]
[slice]
[thud]
I found this place about a week ago.
몇주전에 이 곳을 찾았었어요
약탈자들은 지하에 술과
음식을 넣어두고 실종됐어
Looters missed the stash of
food and booze in the basement.
짐작컨데 모든 좀비는 여기 살았어
Guess all the zombies in
here kept out the rif-raf.
[laughing] Wait 'til I show you
what I've been teaching the locals.
기다려봐, 이 지역에 가르쳐온 걸 보여줄게
카산드라 너 어디갔어?
Cassandra? Hey, where'd you go?
[breathing heavily]
Do you like what I picked out for you?
벗겨 주는거 좋아해?
응
[whispers] Yes.
[breathing heavily]
[snarling]
[screams]
[growling]
[thud]
[Murphy laughs]
[laughing] Don't be afraid. He won't bite.
걱정마 물지않아
And even if he did, you're immune. Remember?
게다가 쟤가 그렇게 해도 넌 괜찮아 기억나?
난 좀비가 아냐
[whispering] I'm not a zombie.
I know.
알어
You're better.
넌 좀 낫지
I've been working on my zombie whispering.
내가 일할 때 내 좀비는 조용히 하지
이리와 보여줘봐
Come on. Let me show you.
This is Telulah and Gigi.
이건 텔루라랑 지지네
Check this out.
밖을 확인해봐
숙녀분들 하던걸 계속해서 보여줘봐
Ladies,
let's show her what you've been working on.
[snarling]
Oh, come on.
오 제발
오 제발 숙녀분들
그건 아니잖아
[snarling] Oh come on, ladies.
That's not right.
야 야 제발
이거에 대해서 얘기 했었다고!
Ladies! Ladies, please!
We talked about this!
[snarling continues]
[moaning]
[teapot whistling]
[clank]
She's awake.
이 분 일어났네
The lady's awake.
그 여자 일어 났어요
Mama, papa
엄마, 아빠
I want you to meet my hero.
내 영웅인 사람을 만나보세요
앉아서 맛있게 드세요
Please, sit down and eat.
You must be starving.
먹어도 되요
Thank you.
고마워요
Five, five, three, seven.
(female voice on radio) Five,
five, three, seven.
Seven, nine, eight, eight, three, four.
Seven, nine, eight,
eight, three, four,
five, one, three, seven.
Five, one, three, seven.
Maybe it's just some giant
cosmic bingo game somewhere.
아마 저건 자이언트 코스믹 빙고게임을
어디간에서 하는 걸거에요
It's probably all just canned
civil defense broadcasts
저건 아마 핵폭탄 때문에 녹음된
시민 방위방송 일거야
triggered by the nukes.
Wow.
(Addy) I just
난 그냥
I just wish we'd hear from somebody.
난 그냥 누군가 들었음 좋겠어
누구든지
Anybody at all
who's alive.
누군가 살았어
[gurgling]
[growling]
Mack!
맥
[gunshot]
Mack!
[growling]
맥
이빨 좀 봐봐
Watch his teeth!
보고 있다고
I'm trying!
Hit him!
쳐버려
확실하게 못치겠어
I can't get a clear shot!
제발
Please!
[growling continues] [screaming continues]
[gunshot]
[splorch]
[thud]
(10K) Three thousand ninety nine!
(Doc yelling) We saw your signal!
당신의 신호를 봤어요
(Warren) You've made a real
life for yourselves here.
여기서 제대로 살고 있었네요
Have some more goat cheese.
고트치즈 좀 더 줄까요?
My husband's been monitoring
the milk for fallout,
제 남편은 방사능낙진을 지켜보고 있어요
헌데, 멀리서 불어온 바람이
우리에게 해를 입히지 않았어요
but so far the winds have spared us.
아니 괜찮아요
No. Thank you.
이미 많이 먹었어요
I've eaten so much already,
my body doesn't know what
the hell is going on.
하두 많이 처먹어서 지옥갈거 같네요
I haven't had real food for weeks.
몇주째 진짜 음식을 못먹었어요
Gave myself up for dead.
자살할려고 했었죠
모두가 그런 생각 햇었죠
We've all been there.
[laughs]
손님이 그리 많지 않았어요
[laughs] We don't get many visitors.
오 어때요
어때?
Oh, how 'bout you? How you doing?
조금씩 나아지겠죠
A lot better.
네
Yeah.
지금 쟨 왜 우리가 가지않고 뿌리내리게
하는지 알고있어요. 혼자서 말이죠
Now she knows why we don't go
digging for roots alone.
전에는 좀비들이 없었어요
There were never zombies there before.
그 망할 핵이에요
It's the damn nukes.
Everything's screwed up now.
Even the weather.
지금은 모든게 꼬였어요
심지어 날씨마저도요
Yeah.
네
Well
음
I have two partners that
are still out there,
전 밖에 살고 있는 두명의 동반자가 있어요
and I should be getting back to them.
그리고 다시 둘을 데려와야죠
All right then.
맞아 그러면
전 뭣좀 싸서 드릴게요
I'm gonna pack you some provisions.
고마워요
Thanks.
Come here.
이리와
All right.
맞아
들었던바로는 여기가
모든 서부로 가는 길이에요
From what I've heard,
everything west of this line here
is a no-go zone. And there's more fallout
여긴 가면안되요
방사능이 깔렸어요
여기랑 여기 넘어서까지요
here and over here.
And I think that's the
tunnel where we crashed.
그리고 내 생각엔 터널이 무너졌어요
그럼 저기서 친구들을 데려올 수 있을까요
So that would put my
friends somewhere in there.
네 산을 이틀 정도 타야할거 같네요
Yeah, that's about a two day hike.
A little less if you go over the mountain.
당신이 산으로 간다면 말이죠
Got it.
- 알았어요
- 그의 얼굴과 손을 핥았다
(girl reading) licking
his face and hands.
그리고 나서 큰걸 꼭 붙잡고
듣고 넘어 뒤로갔다
And so, seizing the larger by
the ears he jumped on his back.
그리고 제일 큰 재미에요
And to my great amusement
coolly rode to meet me as
I came up the hatchway.
쌀살맞게 타고나와 나를 만났다
난 입구에 도착했었다
떠나시나여?
Do you have to go?
응 그렇단다. 아가
Yeah, sweetie.
I have to go.
이제 가야돼
I have a job to do.
할 일을 해야지
Come back and tell us how it turns out.
돌아와서 얘기해줘요 어떻게 됐는지
약속할거죠?
Promise?
응 약속할게
Promise.
Good luck with that Murphy fellow.
멀퓌와 행운을 빌어요 친구
[whispers] Yeah.
응
My husband told me what you did out there.
제 남편이 당신이 밖에서
뭘하는지 얘기해줬어요
그건 정말 끔찍했었어요
It must have been horrible.
I don't know how to thank you.
어떻게 감사하다고 해야할지 모르겠네요
아이들
Those kids
정말 이쁜거 같네요
those beautiful kids.
아이들 만으로도
저에게 감사를 전해줬어요
That's how you'll thank me.
전 이미 죽을 준비가 됐어요
I was ready to die,
and I needed a reason to live.
그리고 전 살아야할 이유가 필요했었죠
저 아이들
Those kids
그게 제 이유가 됐네요
they're the reason.
Thank you.
고마워요
운빨 받길 바래요
Good luck.
Got it.
알았어요
[click]
[motor running]
Oh hey!
오 이봐! 내 스페인어 실력 심각한데
헌데, 이게 뭔지 알겠네
My Spanish is terrible,
but I'm sure this is what
쟤들이 뭘얘기하는지
they were talking about.
다른 방송좀 틀어봐
I wonder who else heard that broadcast.
10시 정오
Ten o'clock!
나 쟤들 봤어 그냥 가버려!
I see them. Just keep going!
셰엔느 사람들은 친절해
Folks are friendly here in Cheyenne.
친절한 분위기가 아냐
느꼇다고
Friendly ain't the vibe I'm getting.
Let's find Murphy and get
the hell out of Dodge.
멀퓌나 찾고
죶같은데서 빨리 나가자
셰엔느
Cheyenne.
뭐든지
Whatever.
좋아 멀퓌가 뭐 필요한지 생각했어
Okay so we all need to think like Murphy.
좀비처럼 변한 걔 머릿속을 느껴보자
Get inside his zombified head.
그리고 여기가 얼마나 섬뜩한지 알았어
And I know that's a scary place to be.
근데 너가 멀퓌라면 어디 숨었을거 같아?
But where would you hide
if you were Murphy?
야 기다려봐
Hey, hold on!
너가 말한 멀퓌냐?
You say think like Murphy?
씨발 쟤들은 저 그림에서 사인을 얻나봐
Hell, they might as well
have his picture on the sign.
이봐 남정네들
Hey, guys.
What the hell took you so long?
얼마나 오래 가져온 줄 알어?
멀퓌 이 개자석
Murphy, you son of a bitch.
응 쟤가 뭘 말하는지 알겠어
Yeah, what she said.
지금 로베르타 오래된 친구랑
어떻게 해서든 말할려고 하는거지?
Now, now, Roberta.
Is that any way to talk to an old friend?
[crash]
[snarling]
Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
[snarling ceases]
그건 아프다고
That hurt.
Oh.
I'm just getting started.
이제 시작했어 이쉐키야
Now come on, Chief. Hey.
Don't forget the mission.
이제 이리와 대빵 이봐 임무를 잊지말라고
그만해
Come on.
You damn near got us killed.
닌 빌어먹을 지인들을 죽였어
그리고 넌 몇백만명을 죽였고
And you did kill millions of other people.
Didn't you get the memo?
기억 안나냐?
핵폭발은 미안하다고도 말 못할 것이야
The Apocalypse means never
having to say you're sorry.
I was just following the prime
directive of this mission.
난 임무의 기본적인 지시를 따랐었어
멀퓌 씹자석을 지켜라
Save Murphy's ass.
Let's not forget.
잊지 않게해
If I die, party's over for the human race.
만약 니가 뒤지면 인류의 미래는 끝나버려
너가 누군가에게 탓하길 원한다면
If you want to blame somebody,
blame that nutjob Doctor Kurian.
그 또라이 쿠리안 박사한테 탓해
혹은 너의 죶만한 좀비친구들한테 하라고
Or your little buddy Citizen Z.
니가 가진 좋은 거땜에 널 묶어야 겠어
Maybe we should tie you
up for your own good.
[hissing]
카산드라
Cassandra.
[hissing]
You're alive.
당신 살아있네여
[hissing]
Cassandra?
What did you do to her?
쟤한테 뭐한거야?
살린거지
뭘 한거야?
Saved her life. What did you do?
[hissing]
미안
쟤 뭘입고 있는거야
I'm sorry. What is she wearing?
너무 터무늬 없는 거 아닌가?
Is that mildly impractical
for the Apocalypse?
너무 고급지게 입은거 아냐?
You try dressing a classy lady in Cheyenne,
Wyoming.
이봐 그 밖에 다른 영향은 없는 거야 ?
Hey, is anybody else concerned that there's
여깃는 모듬 좀비는
이 주변을 서성이는거야?
all these Zs standing around here?
걱정하지마 쟤네 친절하니까
Don't worry. They're friendly.
As long as I'm friendly.
내가 친절하게 하는동안 만큼은 말야
이리와 멀퓌
널 데리고 캘리포니아에 가야겠어
Come on, Murphy.
We got to get you to California.
Yeah. About California
그래 캘리포니아
You know after everything that happened,
the nukes and all
넌 핵폭탄들과 모든 일들이
일어난 다음에 알았지
난 인간적이게 아래서
살아남는게 아니였어
I'm not so sure I'm down with
the whole saving humanity thing.
난 인간적으로 살가치가 없구나
I'm not so sure humanity is worth saving.
넌 캘리포니아에 가야돼
You're going to California.
넌 캘리포니아가 아직
저기라는걸 심지어 몰랐어
You don't even know if
California is still there.
잘봐, 너가 인류를 위해 하지않으면
Well look if you won't do it for humanity,
너 스스로를 위해 해봐 멀퓌
do it for yourself, Murphy.
넌 누구보다 백신이 필요해
You need that vaccine more than anybody.
얼마전에 거울속에 너를 봤잖아?
Have you looked in the mirror lately?
너의 스타일링 그런데
너는 좀비로 돌아갔어, 브로
You may be styling,
but you're turning zombie, brother.
브로
Brother
아마 저기에 좀비보다 더 나쁜게 있어
Maybe there are worse
things than being a zombie.
Maybe being a starving
아마도 굶주림이 시작됐을거야
걱정되고 폭력적이고
fearful
violent
보복하려는 사람들이
vindictive human
염려되네
is worse.
But hey! It is the Apocalypse!
그런데 친구들 그게 바로 파멸이라네
Let's have some fun!
이걸 좀 즐겨봐!
Let me show you what I've been working on.
너가 뭘했는지 좀 봐봐
이리와 의자갖고 넌 이걸 사랑했었어
Come on. Grab a seat.
You're gonna love this.
The Apocalypse will still be
waiting for us when we're done.
파멸은 우리가 자멸할 때를 기다려 줄거야
카산드라
Cassandra!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
아, 만나서 반가웟어. 아주 가족같은 녀석들
Ah, so nice to see so many familiar faces
청중속에 밤을 보내!
in the audience tonight!
Ladies and gentlemen,
신사 숙녀 여러분
let's hear it for the one
한가지를 들어봐봐요
오로지
the only
Chantrelle.
[music plays]
♪
[snarling]
Oh... my... God.
♪
난 쟤가 팁을 위해 일하지 않았음 좋겠어
Well I hope she ain't working for tips.
♪
Whoa. I'm having a déjà vu.
후아 나 이거 본적있어
♪
Murphy.
알어 맞지? 기다려 좋아질거야
I know, right? Wait. It gets better.
♪
[rip]
[crash]
Ta-da!
알어 알어. 피날레는 작은 일해 필요해
I know. I know.
The finale needs a little work.
근데 챈트렐을 위해 들어줘 ㅋㅋ
But hey, let's hear it for Chantrelle!
[laughs]
아 제발!
Oh, come on!
[clap]
개별쇼는 누구든지 볼수 있지?
Is this a private show or can anybody watch?
Ah... ah... ah.
거기 자네들 무기들 내려놓지
Leave your weapons right where they are.
Don't make me have to shoot anybody.
누굴 쏘게하지 말아줘
세상은 이미 좀비로 가득하니까
There's enough zombies
in this world already.
뭘 원하는데?
What do you want?
니 이름이 멀퓌 맞지?
Your name wouldn't happen to be Murphy,
would it?
Nope.
아니
Lot of people looking for you, Mr. Murphy.
- Lot of people looking for you Mr. Murphy.
- That so?
그럼?
이 남잔..
(Warren) This man...
he's our prisoner.
쟨 우리 포로야
Well he's my prisoner now.
음 지금 쟨 우리 포로지
어 미안 쟤말이 맞아 쟤한테 소유권이 있어
Uh no. Sorry. She's right.
We got dibs on him.
응 그리고 캘리포니아에 데려가야돼
Yeah. And we're taking him to California.
아니 넌 안돼
No, you're not.
He's coming with me.
쟨 나랑 갈거야
어딜 ?
Where?
거액을 부른 사람한테 말이지
To the highest bidder.
질병관리본부는 캘리포니아에
오로지 하나밖에 없어
CDC in California aren't the only ones
그위 피를 사려는 사람이 있지
willing to pay for his blood.
왜 모두 항상 나에 대해서 얘기 하지
Why does everybody always talk about me
나처럼 여기 서있찌 않아서?
like I am not standing right here?
넌 모든 해결책이란걸 알고있잖아
You know there's only one
problem with all of your plans
멀퓌를 위해
for The Murphy.
난 쟤말고 다른애랑 같이
어디로 가지 않을거야
I ain't going anywhere with any of you.
물어라
Hit it!
[music plays]
[growling]
♪
[gunshot]
[thud]
[growling]
[gunshot]
[splorch]
[growling]
[stab]
[slice]
[splorch]
[crash]
[growling]
[slice]
[crash]
[growling]
[hit]
[gunshot]
[growling]
[stab]
[slice]
[growling]
[splorch]
We got to get out of here.
여기서 나가야돼
나도 알어
이 음악을 들수 없어
I know. I can't stand this music.
가자
Let's go!
[growling]
[screaming]
♪
[growling]
[hit]
♪
[growling]
[hit]
Warren!
[groaning] [growling]
[zombie growling]
[Warren groaning]
Look out!
[screaming]
[growling]
[pop]
♪
대장 이제 뭐해야돼
What do we do now, Chief?
소녀랑 약속 지켜야돼
I made a promise to a little girl.
지켜나갈거야
And I'm gonna keep it.
멀취 찾아서 캘리포니아에 가야돼
We are going to find Murphy,
get him to California,
그리고 CDC에서 백신을 만들게 해야돼
그리고 세계를 구해야지
and they're going to make a vaccine
and save the world.
And I'm gonna kill any bounty
hunter that gets in my way.
그리고 현상금 사냥꾼을
죽이고 내 갈길 가야지
Sounds like a plan.
좋은 계획이구만
멀퓌가 간거 빼고 다른 생각은 없는건가?
Any idea which way Murphy went?
[tires squealing]
쟨 저기로 갔어
He went that way.
[dog whining]
좋아 문제 될건 없어 넌 여깄어
[whispering] Okay.
No matter what happens, you stay.
착하지
That's a good boy.
[clank]
Remember
기억해
너가 뭘듣던 문제돼지 않아
no matter what you hear,
넌 기다려
you stay.
좋아 아가
Okay, sweetie.
Which way is daddy?
아빠 어딨니?
Left it is.
그는 떠났단다
제작 : 똥자막
세라야 사랑해